Do you remember learning
about modern natural right
from Professor Baer
before spring break?
Yes, a bit.
We studied Locke's state of
nature and its connection
with natural right, if that's
what you're talking about.
Professor Baer
also made the case
that modern natural right is the
basis for the American regime
and the reason for
this country's success.
Good.
And yes, that is
exactly what I mean.
It's great that you
remember reading
Locke and about
modern natural right
being the basis for
the American regime.
Oh.
Hello, Professor Knowles.
What are you doing here?
I hope I'm not bothering you.
I heard that you were
discussing modern natural right,
and I wanted to join.
Please do join us.
We were just starting
on modern natural right.
So how does Locke view the
problem of AI and bias?
Patch.
Locke would think it
wrong because bias
violates your natural right.
Yes, I agree.
That sounds right,
but I'm not sure
because we said that justice is
more important than equality.
But it seems that equality
is fundamental in Locke.
But then where is
justice in Locke?
Let's take this step by step.
Does anyone remember
the beginning?
But you said you were
working on these questions
during spring break.
Alvis?
Well, we were discussing them,
but we never actually went back
to the texts from class.
Yeah.
We just wanted to figure
them out for ourselves.
I guess you disapprove,
Professor Muller?
On the contrary.
You are a very
impressive group to have
stayed here over spring
break and investigated
these questions.
Any teacher would be thrilled to
have even one student like you,
and I have five.
But you said that you got stuck.
What was your plan to
get out of your impasse?
Well, your class, of course.
[LAUGHS]
Hush, Patch.
You seem not to realize
that Professor Muller is
in a most mild way
rebuking us for not
using the resources at hand.
Well, let's use them now.
Professor, please remind us
of Locke's starting point.
Of course.
Let's turn to second
treatise, chapter 1.
Professor Knowles, where do
you think we should start?
I'd say the last section
of paragraph one,
starting with "he that."
That is exactly
what I was thinking.
Glenda, could you
read the statement
starting with "he that?"
Of course.
He that will not
give just occasion
to think that all
government in the world
is the product of only
force and violence
must of necessity find out
another rise of government.
Good.
So Locke is giving
us two options
of the origin of government,
force or something else--
maybe something
else based on reason
but not narrow or
mathematical reason.
Yes, of course.
That is much better.
It would be terrible to
think that politics is just
about force.
I agree.
It should be about
allowing people
to be happy, as we said before.
But what does this
alternative basis?
You can look at your
books, you know.
Alvis.
It is the state of nature.
Good.
What is the state of nature?
Well, let's see.
I actually underlined
this pretty extensively.
It is a state of perfect freedom
and a state also of equality.
Yes.
I remember now.
But how can it be a
state of perfect freedom
if anyone can take your
stuff and it's only up to you
to protect it?
You don't remember?
That's the point.
There is no government,
so we're all
perfectly free in that sense.
But life is not
desirable since we're
all individually vulnerable.
That's why we form
governments, for security.
Very good, Sophie, but
you're moving too fast.
Remember Locke says but though
this be a state of liberty,
yet it is not a
state of license.
Do you recall why that is?
Oh, hold on.
I have it right here.
Because of a law of nature.
Yes, that's it.
Laws of nature are
based on reason.
Yeah.
We talked about that
before spring break.
Now I remember.
It's dumb to waste stuff,
including your own life.
What about these people
that waste their money
on luxuries, expensive
cars and things?
Yeah.
I'd be content with
a cheap rundown car.
Why should someone buy a
Ferrari when most of us
can't afford an old Kia?
Does anyone recall
Locke's answer to this?
Perhaps, once again,
we are moving too fast.
Let's go step by step.
What is the state
of nature like?
Alvis.
In addition to freedom and
equality, there is a law.
Good.
What else?
There is punishment.
In paragraph seven, he
says everyone has a right
to punish the transgressors
of that law to such a degree
as may hinder its violation.
Very good, Sophie.
I think we will see that
our objection to bias
is itself based on a sense
that there is a law of nature.
How does Locke characterize
this statement?
He says in paragraph nine that
this will seem a very strange
doctrine to some.
Excellent.
Does it seem strange to you?
Well, not any more strange
than the state of nature.
Why is the state
of nature strange?
So nature is what you
experience when you go on a hike
or go camping.
What Locke is describing
never really existed.
What do you think
existed in its place?
So humans evolved
from humanoids,
and they lived in tribes.
They weren't by themselves.
Right, Patch.
But what is the basis of the
rule of the tribe leader?
Power.
But isn't this exactly what
Locke said at the beginning?
We can have tribal
rule based on power,
or we can have an alternative,
which Locke provides.
Besides, don't you think
human beings' natural state is
freedom and equality?
That all makes sense.
But then why does Locke call
it a very strange doctrine?
To some.
See, I think that will
find that what is required
is not so much a new doctrine,
say a learned latent structure
for algorithmic bias mitigation
or domain adaptation,
but a reflection
on what doctrine
some find strange
and others do not.
What's strange to us actually
contradicts our own biases.
Psychologically, we tend
to resist those things
because they point out
our biases to ourselves.
Oh, I see.
What we find strange is an
indication of our own bias.
That's what Locke is saying.
Thank you, Professor Knowles.
And I realize that he
defends this doctrine
by arguing that governments
can punish foreigners
who break a law,
which is related
to the example in
paragraph 14, when he says
that by the state of nature
exists today, since all princes
and rulers of
independent governments
all through the world
are in a state of nature.
Very good, and then he
brings in the next paragraph
the weight of the writings
of Hooker, or shall
we say the judicious Hooker.
And he ends the chapter
with the idea of consent.
So political society is made
legitimate only by consent.